Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin collection of American history miscellany, [circa 1776-1933].
Rudin, Gail and Stephen collection of American history miscellany
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gail and Stephen Rudin collection of American history miscellany, [circa 1776-1933].
6995
Rudin, Stephen,
.1 cubic feet.
Correspondence, printed materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Documents related to various events in Unites States history. Includes items related to the Revolutionary War and the War of 1812, a Washington, D.C. lottery ticket, and prescriptions for alcohol written during Prohibition.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Documents related to various events in Unites States history. Includes items related to the Revolutionary War and the War of 1812, a Washington, D.C. lottery ticket, and prescriptions for alcohol written during Prohibition.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rudin, Stephen, -- collector
Subjects:
Prohibition -- United States.
Places:
United States -- History.; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783.; United States -- History -- War of 1812.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Forms part of the Eastern Wine and Grape Archive. (EWGA)
CONTAINER LIST
- Enlistment Bounty, December 15, 1777 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Bounty for 74 Pounds for enlisting in The Continental Army.
  Rudin # M-43
- John Demmon enlistment, June 27, 1776 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Soldier John Demmon enlists in the Continental Army, CT.
  Rudin # M-58
- Lottery Ticket, November 18, 1776 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Ticket 59 m 664 Class the Fourth for the U.S. Lottery to help finance the American Revolutionary War. Signed by J. Bullock.
  Rudin # M-79
- Ticket 28 m 820 Class the First for the U.S. Lottery to help finance the American Revolutionary War. Signed by J. Searle., November 18, 1776 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Rudin # M-80
- Wallpaper enlistment, 1813 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Paper shortages necessitated use of patterned wallpaper for some military documents. Enlistment of John Coffman. Maryland.
  Rudin # M-99
- The Star Spangled Banner, April 2, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Printed broadside announcing the bill (H.R. 91) proposing that the Star Spangled Banner be declared the National Anthem.
  Rudin # M-96
- Prohibition prescriptions for alcohol, April 25, 1925 and May 7, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Prohibition prescription for "one pint Rye Whiskey" for James Kelley. Accompanied by a second prescription for Whiskey for James Denby, this being a duplicate to be retained by the druggist.
  Rudin # M-89
- Two lottery tickets, ca. 1800 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Washington City Canal Lottery for cutting the canal through the city of Washington to the Eastern Branch Harbour. One ticket signed by Notley Young and one signed by Daniel Carroll.
  Rudin # M-81
- Three almanacs, 1855, 1871, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Hagerstown, Agricultural Almanac, Hagerstown
  Rudin # M-105
- Confederate envelopes, circa 1860s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Group of five Confederate hand-made adversity envelopes made from a variety of paper products including bank and legal documents, bill of lading documents, and advertising broadsides. Postally used.
  Rudin # M-86
- American flag, January 2, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  This Congressional Report fixes the ultimate design and evolution of the American Flag as we know it today.
  Rudin # M-94A
- The Star Spangled Banner, November, 1814 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  First magazine printing of the poem that became the National Anthem. (From "The Analectic Magazine" - Nov. 1814).
  Rudin # M-95
- Oath of Allegiance, ca. 1780s (Map-case DD-17)
  Oath of Allegiance to State of New York and renouncing of allegiance to King of Great Britain. Signed by more than 50 local New York patriots.
  Rudin # M-102
- Descriptive list of 26 deserters from Malone, New York, October, 1863 (Map-case DD-17)
  Rudin # M-76C
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Bound Volumes
Scientific American, 1861. Rudin # M-56